Dimitri Dwyer

London, UK +447415 930659

Email: dimitridwyer@hotmail.co.uk

GitHub: github.com/dimitri12482 Portfolio: DimitriDwyer.com

Profile

Full Stack Developer who's experience in all layers of the stack and enjoy building out user friendly efficient websites. Demonstrating that I have a proven system in place when I take on a project and that I understand how to produce real results for your business. a strong knowledge of the languages that make up WordPress (HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and PHP) and have worked to build sites from scratch and modify and manipulate themes and plugins.

Technical Skills

Languages: HTML5; CSS; SQL; JavaScript; Node; PHP; JJRA; Java

Frameworks: React; jQuery; Express; Laravel; Bootstrap; MongoDB; Spring

Professional Experience

HCA Healthcare UK

Nov 2020 - Present

Front Engineer:

- Using technology to solve business problems with creativity & innovation.
- Experience using JIRA, Microsoft Visual Studio Team Services and similar task management tools.
- Set up a portfolio site to show off the projects using Node.js and Express for fast, modular and dynamic web applications.
- Constructed a system management application for listing, adding, updating, and deleting books in a library application, using JavaScript, Node.js, Express, Pug, and the SQL ORM Sequelize.
- Design a REST API that lets users create, read, update, and delete items from a school database using Express web application framework and a SQL database.
- Good understanding of build tools and package managers such as NPM, Grunt, Gulp or Webpack
- Ensure cross-browser, cross-platform, and multiple device type compatibility for all web solutions.

Team Treehouse

July 2020 – Present

Web Developer:

- Managing and communicating client expectations using remote tools such as Zoom and Google Hangouts.
- Integrating third-party systems such as Strapi (Content Management System and Stripe (Payment system).
- Installed a WordPress theme for online jewellery detailer and adjusted style based on client requests using PHP and Laravel.
- Set-up monitoring alerts for applications and environments.

Technical Projects

E-commerce Store

Built a fully functional eCommerce application using commerce.js and React. This project is focus on operating as an online store where you can add items to a shopping cart and have checkout page.

Expense Tracker App

This project focuses on your expense and income which helps everybody to make their daily productivity organised. The languages that are used for this project are React.js Material UI and Context API. I even added voice capabilities to command applications using Speechly which allows the user to command their next expense or income.

Tetris Game

Create a tile-matching puzzle game from the 80's, using HTML, CSS and JavaScript. This allows you to have your personal high score by moving each of the 5 randomly selected Tetris shapes sideways and/or rotating by quarter-turns, so that they form a solid horizontal line without gaps.

Education

Team Treehouse

Nov 2020 - Present

Full Stack JavaScript Tech Degree

Freecodecamp

June 2020 - Present

• Software Engineering Certification

Interests and Activities

Practiced coding interview questions on hackathons. Helped me to develop skills, experiences and ideas beyond my course. BCS (British Computer Society) member. Keep up to date with developments in IT.